https://www.scimed.co.uk/privacy-policy/

MenuHomeAbout CloseCareer and Job OpportunitiesCompany HistoryCompany PhilosophyOur PartnershipInformation for Staying near SciMed OfficesProducts CloseElectron Microscopy CloseScanning Electron MicroscopyIon Beam MillingMechanical PreparationElemental Analysis CloseAtomic Absorption Spectroscopy (AAS)Chloride AnalyserCombustion Analysis (C/N/S/Cl)Flame PhotometersICP-MSICP-OESLIBSX-Ray Fluorescence (XRF) CloseED-XRF BenchtopED-XRF Hand HeldWD-XRFTXRFOnline XRFCoating Thickness MeasurementXRF Sample Preparation/ConsumablesElectrochemistryGlass Jacketed VesselsGeneral Labware CloseBalancesChillersPowder DryerReagents/StandardsSample PreparationHydrogen GeneratorLab Scale Pressure Vessels CloseStirred Reactors CloseThe 5500 SeriesThe 4500 Series CloseThe 4590 SeriesThe 4560 SeriesThe 4520 SeriesThe 4540 SeriesThe 4570 SeriesThe 4530 SeriesThe 4550 SeriesThe 4555 SeriesThe 4580 SeriesMulti Reactor Systems CloseThe MBS 2500The MRS 5000Multi-Vessel Set-upsNon-Stirred Vessels CloseThe 4700 SeriesThe 4740 SeriesThe 4790 SeriesThe 4750 SeriesThe 4760 SeriesThe 4600 SeriesThe 4650 SeriesThe 4660 SeriesThe 4670 SeriesThe 4680 SeriesTubular ReactorsCustom designed systemsControllersAccessoriesAcid Digestion VesselsShaker HydrogenatorsMaterial Characterisation CloseDensity MeasurementGas HumidityGas SorptionParticle Sizing & Zeta PotentialPolarimetersPowder Flow TestingRefractometersSpecific Saturation MagnetisationX-Ray Diffraction (Powder, Thin Film and SAXS)X-ray TomographyNear Infra Red Spectroscopy CloseBenchtop Infra-CalHand Held SpectrometerOnlineOil Condition MonitoringPetroleum Testing CloseFlash PointKinematic ViscosityLubricant and Grease TestingProcess Safety Contract TestingRheometers CloseBenchtopHand Held Raman SpectroscopySupercritical CO2 ProcessesThermal Methods and Analysis CloseDifferential Scanning CalorimetryEvolved Gas AnalysisThermogravimetric AnalysisAdiabatic CalorimetersCalorimetryO2 Bomb CalorimeterTotal Organic Carbon – Total NitrogenUltrasonic ProcessingUV-VIS CloseBenchtopHand Held Raman SpectroscopyViscometersMarket sectorsMeet the TeamEducationSeminars & TrainingNewsEnquirySciMed Privacy PolicyProtecting your dataYour privacy is very important to us, which is why we make sure you are always in control of what we do with your personal information.Our commitmentWe will never pass your personal details to anyone outside SciMed for them to use for their own marketing purposes unless you have previously provided us with your informed and specific consent.We will ensure that we obtain your express consent before we contact you by email for any purpose.We will make sure our contact with you is relevant, based upon the preference information you give us.You can change your contact preferences at any time. All you need to do is update your preferences by contacting us at enquiries@scimed.co.uk.We do not willingly store any private personal information, since we are a Business to Business organisaiton.Your work contact information will be stored safely and will remain secure at all times.No statistical information which identifies you personally will be published.No personal information will be kept any longer than necessary in order to fulfill the purpose it was collected for, and if you ask us to, it will be deleted.We will always delete your information if requested by you to do so, providing you are not a current user of one of our products. In which case these details are required to maintain your user records.We will always comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 and all other applicable laws and EU Directives.Please let us know if your details change so that we can keep in touch.The information we collectWe collect information to provide either keep our customer records or to send out product and event information such as : newsletters, product updates, invitaitons to training courses, masterclasses, seminar and open days. This information may include your name, work postal address, business telephone number, business fax number, business e-mail address.We collect information in the following ways:Collecting  data when you register or update your personal details using online enquiry forms and accounts, or over the phone.Recording data through cookiesCollecting other information from you from time to time at conferences and exhibitions.We track automatically the home server domain names, IP addresses, type of visitor computer, type of web browser of visitors to our websites, and specific information on what pages our visitors accessUsing your informationSciMed will process your data (for example your name, address, email address, country of residence) in accordance with your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998. We may process your information in any number of ways and on any databases we use for the following purposes:To create an electronic record of your data to enable your request for information to be processedTo help us manage your product service record or other services we provide to youTo administer and manage the products and services we make available to youTo compile delegate lists for use at our events, or for advertising future courses and events promoting  SciMed Products and services.To help us identify products and services which we think will interest you (unless you have asked us not to)We may also communicate with you, on behalf of other organisations, should you opt in to receiving third party communications.Sharing your informationWe take our obligations and responsibilities regarding protecting your privacy very seriously, and therefore, we exercise great care to protect the information we collect about you.We will share your information outside of SciMed only in the following circumstances:You have provided your express prior consent, and the contractor or organisation is working directly with us as a partner as a part of maintaining our activities, products, or services. Service providers and suppliers are required to keep confidential and secure the personal information received from us and may not use it for any other purpose other than as originally intended.To our suppliers for operational reasonsIf compelled by law to do so.Communication preferences & changes to personal detailsOnce you have provided your express consent for us to contact you on our behalf, or on behalf of other organisations, there are a number of methods available to you in order to change your preferences, to correct or update your personal information at any time by:clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any promotional email you receive from uscontacting our product or service team where a correction is requiredcontacting us at enquiries@scimed.co.ukProtecting informationWe use a Secure Site License (SSL) approved technology where appropriate.Pages that use this technology are flagged with a padlock symbol.We use secure technology in all our email communications and unless you have provided us with your clear and express consent, we do not disclose your email address to any other recipient.CookiesWhat is a cookie?A cookie is text file that is stored on your computer or mobile device by a website’s server. Each cookie contains anonymised information about how you use our websites and applications, which allows us to improve your experience of using our products and services.Disabling cookiesIf you prefer, it is possible to disable cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features on our websites if cookies are disabled.SciMed Privacy Policy for the InternetSciMed is dedicated to protecting the privacy of the personally identifiable information our customers choose to share with us. We follow the principles of disclosure and choice, which allow SciMed to provide desired information and services to our customers while protecting their personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information that can be associated with a specific individual or entity, including, for example, a customer’s name, address, or telephone number, e-mail address, personal preferences and information about on-line activities that are directly linked to him/her.Not everyone chooses to share personally identifiable information just because they visit a site. When you provide your contact details on our Enquiry page, these details might be added to our central contact database. You  have the right to ask for these details not to be added to this database, or to change your mind in the future, and you can view your profile (in real time in most cases) to make changes or withdraw your consent to receive information, or for other uses of your personally identifiable information.Our website may send a ‘cookie’, a small summary file of who you are, to your computer to give you the courtesy of instant recognition the next time you visit, without bothering you with another request to register. If you do not wish to be recognised refer to your Internet Browser to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored.This website collects personally identifiable information that the web site uses to service our customers’ individual needs and interests. This is the primary use of personally identifiable information.This website may also from time to time share personally identifiable information and/or aggregated data with responsible partner companies. Such aggregated data may include, statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information.This website provides links to other websites, especially to our suppliers. You should carefully review the privacy policies on those sites; they may differ from the SciMed privacy policy.SciMed’s relationship with its customers is at the core of all we do. We seek to know you better so we can serve you better, but the choice of whether you want that kind of service is up to you. If for some reason you believe SciMed has not adhered to these principles, please notify us by email or post, and we will  promptly determine and correct the problem.Right to request a correctionYou can request that we correct or update your personal data at any time to ensure that your information is accurate and up-to-date.Right to be forgottenWe may be required to archive your personal information however, we will not retain personal data for longer than is necessary for the purpose we obtained it and only in accordance with our Document Retention Policy.  You have the right to request that we delete your personal information in certain circumstances, ie where the purpose for collecting your personal information no longer exists and we are not obligated to retain all or any part of your personal information for legal reasons.Suppression listsWe will not contact you about our related products or services or send you any other communications if you have indicated that you do not want to receive these. In this case, your name will be included in appropriate suppression lists.Withdrawing your consentYou can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at enquiries@scimed.co.uk.Our right to change this privacy statementThis Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will indicate at the top of the statement when it was most recently updated. We recommend that you visit our Privacy Statement page whenever you visit our websites so that you are aware of any changes.
